usaudiomart.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy - US Audio Mart

Welcome to USAudioMart, a classifieds site for used audio and hifi. Postings are **free** for hobbyists. [Register today](https://www.usaudiomart.com/register.php) and start selling/buying audio gear!

## US Audio Mart's Privacy Policy

We here at US Audio Mart and its Operators, Canuck Digital Media Inc. recognize that the relationship with our visitors is one of our most valuable assets. We therefore understand and respect the need for protecting your privacy in order to establish trust and to maintain the integrity of our company. We have provided the following Privacy Policy for US Audio Mart (www.canuckaudiomart, "we" or "us") disclosing the purpose, intent, collection, use, and protection of any information that is potentially private. 

This document was last updated May 28th 2018.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect on our site and when you sign up or use our services. 

Note: This policy only applies to any information disclosed while dealing directly with US Audio Mart (https://www.usaudiomart.com/). Once you leave our web site to go to another web site, or provide information to other users of the site, we cannot assume responsibility of any information that may be collected, disclosed, and/or manipulated by those other services or users. 

_**About the Information We Collect:**_

Visitors of US Audio Mart are not asked to disclose information involutarily except for whatever information is always disclosed by browsers, servers, and internet traffic as part of the normal operation of a website. Some of that information automatically disclosed is explained under the heading "Log Files" and "Cookies". US Audio Mart does not collect private information such as emails, names, and addresses from its users without their knowledge.

To make full use of our services you must register for a free account and will be asked to provide personal information (i.e. any information that can identify an individual). You must voluntarily disclose this information if you wish to create an account in order to post in our forum or post in our classifieds and auctions, but you do not need to register on the site in order to browse the site and see classifieds. 

It is not necessary to register an account to reply to most ads, but some sellers require that only registered users can reply to their ads. We do not control which ads require registration and which do not, this is a facility decided by the owners of those ads and those who elect to require registered user replies may do so as an anti-fraud measure. 

Throughout the site there may be forms that you can submit to the site. This includes forms to register, post classified ads, post forum posts, and respond to classifieds. Please know that when you submit a form on our site we collect this information along with browser information in order to operate the service properly and safely. Do not submit forms if you do not wish the information in the form to be processed by us. 

As with many other sites, registration and other services may require the use of cookies and/or the propagation of session information. Cookies and sessions information help facilitate and make the visit to our site more "user friendly," but we still treat them as personal information and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can see the heading titled "Cookies" for more details on our use of cookies. 

For safety and security purposes, we keep a record of time, browser information, and ISP information for certain actions performed while a user is logged in. This information is used strictly for debugging and security purposes (such as identifying unauthorised usage of an account), is not public and can only be accessed by site administrators and moderators.

The collection and storage of information such as ISP, IP, and browser information for certain actions on the site is considered a critical anti-fraud, anti-scam and safety process and is integral to keeping our community and marketplace safe from bad actors seeking to harm and take defraud our users. Because there is no reasonable alternative to storing and processing this information, and because not having this information puts our users at significant risk, we collect this pseudo anonymous information under Legitimate Interest basis and do not require or request consent for its collection from EU visitors. 

_**Use and Disclosure of the Information We Collect:**_

US Audio Mart will only use the aforementioned information to facilitate your transactions on our site, maintain security and safety in our marketplace, and to enhance you overall experience of the site. 

Some of the information you provide is displayed in your classified listings or user profile, such as your Country, State, and City.

Your email is not displayed to the public when you post a classified listing, however, your email address is disclosed to the owners of any classifieds that you reply to so that they may respond to your inquiries. 

When you respond to a classified on the site, we store a copy of the response as well as your email address and time of response so that the person you are responding to can read your message and reply to them. Only the owner of the ad, and site Administrators and moderators can see this information.

We collect, store and process browser and location information such as your IP and browser type when you list an ad, reply to an ad, or post in our forums. This information is kept for security purposes and is only accessible by site administrators and site appointed moderators.

We do NOT sell, lease, rent, or in any way make available to third parties, any information that is linkable to you individually that you provided us, without express consent from you as indicated through information forms that you voluntarily fill out. 

US Audio Mart will take reasonable precautionary measures to protect and safeguard all information gathered about you while using our site. US Audio Mart does not, however, take any responsibility for any breach of security, accidental disclosure, theft, or tampering of your information. 

_**Log Files:**_

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site. Site visitors do not have access to this information. 

_**Cookies:**_

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer by our servers. Cookies are not used by us to store any personal information on your computer. Instead, the most common usage of cookies is for the purpose of maintaining a login session or storing non-personal preferences. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies.

Session ID cookies are required for the proper functioning of the site, or else you cannot stay logged in.

A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. This type of cookie is used mostly in our forum and for storing non-personally revealing preferences such as whether to show Grid Mode or List mode when browsing the site. 

Many aspects of the site will not operate properly if you reject or delete our first party cookies as they are critical to the proper operation of the site and there are no alternatives we can rely on for those aspects of our operation. Therefore we consider first party cookies to be valid based on Legitimate Interest basis and do not request nor require consent to set these cookies in the browsers of even EU users. However, if you do decide to reject and delete our cookies, know that you can still browse the site, you just cannot log in and participate as a registered user, and some pages may not display as you expect.

_**Third Party Analytics:**_

US Audio Mart uses Google Analytics to get an idea of how our site is used and to help improve our service. Certain information such as your browser, and your IP address may be sent to Analytics but this information is always anonymized so that we don’t know which specific visitors are associated with what browser and we do not have access to any IP information in Google Analytics. Analytics may use several cookies including cookies stored for very long periods in order to determine if you have visited the site before, but Analytics never associates any identifiable information with your visit. So we may know many people visit a particular page, but we won’t know specifically who read it. 

To opt out of being counted in Google Analytics, you can install a [ browser add on made by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

To read more about Google's use of information please [see their disclosure here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). 

_**Banner and Third Party Advertising:**_

The banner ads appearing on US Audio Mart are delivered to users by our adserver and our advertising partners including Google Ads. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). 

You can find out more about Google's [information use here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). 

You can control Ad Personalisation by Google Ads and Google products by visiting the [Google Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/). 

You can also learn more about other third party advertiser personalisation of ads and opt out of personalisation by [seeing this opt out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). 

_**Your Consent:**_

By using our web site (https://www.usaudiomart.com/), it constitutes acceptance of the details outlined in this Privacy Policy. US Audio Mart reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. 

If you are a user in the EU, you must consent to the usage of your information when you register on our site. 

**_Privacy Contact Info:_**

Canuck Digital Media Inc.  
P.O. Box 27531  
Oakridge  
Vancouver, BC, Canada  
V5Z 4M4
